Yizhou "Harry" Tian

SUMMARY

My research interest lies in in Human-AI interaction (HAI). I aim to building more effective and responsible human-AI collaboration by leveraging AI that model humans. Currently, I am interested in (i) designing human-compatible decision support systems and AI teaching frameworks and (ii) the gap between HAI experiments on laypeople and practitioners.

EDUCATION

University of Chicago

2021 - Present

M.S. in Computer Science, Pre-Doctoral program

Advisor: Chenhao Tan

Relevant Coures: Fundamentals of Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Mathematical Foundations of Machine Learning, Human-Centered Machine Learning

Carleton College 2017 - 2021

B.A. in Computer Science and Linguistics

Research Experience

Research Assistant - University of Chicago

Sep 2021 - present

Chicago Human+AI Lab

- Designed case-based decision support system using human-compatible representations, ran human studies on natural image and medical image datasets.
- Work in progress: Building AI-driven tutorial for radiology residents training on prostate cancer diagnosis. Experimenting on contrastive learner models.

Research Assistant - REU at University of Minnesota

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

Advisor: Zhiwei Steven Wu

- Experimented on hyperparameter optimization methods on differentially private algorithms and concluded that Random Search outperforms Bayesian Optimization in the general case.
- Created and presented research poster in virtual National REU Poster Symposium

Research Assistant - REU at University of North Texas

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Learned and experimented with neural networks and text encoders.

Publications

Learning human-compatible representations for case-based decision support

Han Liu, Yizhou Tian, Chacha Chen, Shi Feng, Chen Yuxin, and Chenhao Tan. (Under Review)

Towards effective case-based decision support with human-compatible representations Han Liu, Yizhou Tian, Chacha Chen, Shi Feng, Chen Yuxin, and Chenhao Tan. In Proceedings of the 1st ICML 2022 Workshop on Human-Machine Collaboration and Teaming (HMCaT, ICML 2022)

Relevant Skills

Programming Languages: Python, HTML5, C, Java,

Packages & Platforms: Pytorch, Django, Numpy, Pandas, git

Professional Experience

Software Engineer Extern - FormFast

Nov2018 - Dec 2018

St. Louis, MO

FormFast, healthcare eForms company

- Shadowed developers in working process, learned software development basics.

- Created blood bank management Windows App using C#.

Latin American History course Teaching Assistant - JNC

July 2018 - Aug 2018

JNC International Summer School

Guangzhou, China

STUDY ABROAD EXPERIENCE

Computer Science Study Abroad Program

AIT Budapest

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

Budapest, Hungary

LSE-PKU Summer School

Aug 2018

Coursework: Big Data: Data Analytics for Business and Beyond

Beijing, China

Last updated: December 10, 2022